

Atlanta, GA

■ resume@woneill.com | 😭 woneill.com | 🖸 woneill | 🛅 williamoneill

# **Summary**

Staff SRE/DevOps with a broad range of experiences where I have increased team velocity through the use of infrastructure as code, optimized build and release pipelines, and ensuring that developers have safe and complete testing environments available.

# **Work Experience**

#### Momentive Inc., maker of SurveyMonkey

San Mateo, CA (remote)

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SRE October 2021 - Current

ReCharge Payments Santa Monica, CA (remote)

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

June 2020 - October 2021

- Implemented CI processes for Terraform and Ansible code bases. This reduced peer review cycle time from 2-3 days to under 1 day and lowered error rates plus improved documentation.
- Created standardized pattern for Terraform stacks which enabled feature teams to safely self-service their own infrastructure. This removed the dependency on the infrastructure teams and led to feature teams quickly implementing their necessary infrastructure.
- Designed a candidate tech lab as an additional vetting process during the team's interview cycle.
- Improved individualized developer testing environments by implementing Let's Encrypt SSL certificates and OAuth based authorization.

Teachers Pay Teachers

New York, NY (remote)

**DEVOPS TECH LEAD** 

March 2019 - June 2020

- Coordinated transition from larger operations team to Cloud Operations focused infrastructure team.
- Drove improvements to processes so that requests from development teams were fulfilled in a consistent manner. These changes enabled the Cloud Operations team to implement SLOs for most common requests.

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER December 2018 - March 2019

- Coordinated the audit process to achieve PCI Level 1 certification. Improvements to the process reduced the time to perform the audit from multiple weeks down to 2 days.
- Delivered an automated function to understand and forecast AWS EC2 Reserved Instance needs.
- Developed Terraform modules that encapsulated best practices for infrastructure hosted on AWS.

Spreedly Durham, NC (remote)

SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER

- Championed 'infrastructure as code' for existing co-located servers and refactored for a migration to AWS.
- Evolved deployments from 'snowflakes' to immutable infrastructure via Ansible, Packer, and Terraform.

**GE Digital** Atlanta, GA

LEAD INFRASTRUCTURE AUTOMATION ENGINEER

August 2016 - May 2017

May 2017 - November 2018

- Improved automation of the wing to wing monitoring of network and compute assets.
- Consolidated monitoring tool sprawl by creating business unit dashboards.
- Developed an 'easy button' for the first contact helpdesk which empowered them to do tasks such as pinging hosts, checking application status, and even reboot machines with supervisor approval.
- Implemented full lifecycle deployment of microservices via Jenkins for builds, Sphinx/Swagger generated documentation, artifact storage in Artifactory, and final deployment via Ansible.

MailChimp Atlanta, GA

SENIOR INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER

April 2015 - May 2016

- Migrated high traffic DNS domains from a provider that billed based on usage to Akamai. This reduced costs since billing was no longer traffic based and increased the SLA for DNS.
- Consolidated hundreds of domain names spread across several registrars to one registrar. This made management of domain names more consistent, provided visibility into domain names that should be added or dropped as necessary, and enabled creation of a customized 'parked page' for unused domains.
- Helped move MailChimp from 3rd party managed hosting operations to self-managed colocation datacenters. This move reduced operations costs, improved service reliability, and provided a model for future server growth.
- Subject matter expert on testing Puppet prior to deploying to production. Designed a common template for new Puppet modules that includes testing run via Docker instances.

Infrastructure Engineer October 2012 - April 2015

• Helped scale the operations team from 3 people to 40 engineers. This involved documentation of the greenfield datacenter implementations, tech talks on subjects such as Puppet development, infrastructure testing, and 1-on-1 mentorship.

- Implemented configuration management using Puppet, replacing an in-house configuration management tool who's development had been abandoned
- Developed internal tooling that automatically provisioned servers from 'rack and stack' bare metal to a fully installed OS registered with an in-house CMDB.

### Intercontinental Exchange, Inc.

Atlanta, GA

SYSTEMS ENGINEER March 2010 - October 2012

Managed >4000 Solaris, Linux, AIX and Windows nodes spread across 6 data centers. Implemented Puppet to manage server configurations that had been manually configured via an error prone process.

Employease Atlanta, GA

SENIOR CONFIGURATION ENGINEER

June 2008 - March 2010

Managed the construction and provisioning of environments that support the software as a service (SaaS) transition through development, QA, and production deployments.

CheckFree (now Fisery)

Atlanta, GA

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR/CONFIGURATION ENGINEER

November 2005 - May 2008

Managed the build and unit testing of Biller Solutions software across multiple platforms including Linux, Solaris, AIX, HPUX and Windows servers.

**Arris** Atlanta, GA

SENIOR SYSTEMS Administrator

January 2001 - November 2005

Maintained and provided end user support for firmware developer tools such as ClearCase, CVS, RCS, and various compiler suites.

Collective Technologies Atlanta, GA

CONSULTANT June 1998 - November 2000

Consulted on projects including designing the email infrastructure for a California school district, architecting metrics collection from satellite downlink stations, and teaching a two-week "crash course" on UNIX System Administration to a Big 5 accounting firm training class.

## Skills\_

Platforms Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Linux (CentOS/Red Hat, Ubuntu/Debian), Docker, Kubernetes, EKS, GKE

**Technologies** Git, Terraform, Vault, Helm, Ansible, Puppet, Chef, Packer, Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD

**Languages** Shell, Python, Ruby, Node.js

# **Presentations**

PAYMENTSfn 2018 Durham, NC

Raising Children vs Raising Rabbits

May 2018

- A lightning talk about the tooling behind Spreedly's cloud instances and how compliance and security are built into the process.
- https://confreaks.tv/videos/paymentsfn2018-raising-children-vs-raising-rabbits

### **GitHub Octotales**

OCTOTALES: MAILCHIMP March 2016

- GitHub's video profile of MailChimp and their use of GitHub Enterprise. My favorite quote: "As an infrastructure guy, code is our poetry."
- https://youtu.be/OeBZUW-9iOM

Atlanta Puppet Camp

Atlanta, GA

CONTINUOUS DEPLOYMENT OF PUPPET MODULES

December 2014

- Presentation about how MailChimp uses a combination of DSL tooling, editor plugins, peer review, and Jenkins to do continuous deployment of puppet modules to their infrastructure.
- https://youtu.be/81os\_qau\_0c

### **Education**

Temple University

Philadelphia, PA

BACHELOR OF ARTS, MASS COMMUNICATION